Raymond Raleigh

Dublin Road, Longford, Co. Longford | 086 3080848 | raymondraleigh@gmail.com

Profile Summary:

A final year student of the Bachelor of Science (Hons) in Business Information Systems from Galway-Mayo Institute of Technology. I have developed skills in web development using HTML and CSS, business analysis, database management and project management. I have completed a number of group projects as part of the course which has greatly improved my communication, leadership and team work skills.

Over the course of my internship at Dell Technologies I have developed my skills in time management and communication, particular when I had to work from home. As well as learning how Dell's supply chain works. My work experience through my families businesses in the service and retail sectors has improved my skills in customer service, leadership and problem solving.

Education:

2017-2021: BSc (Hons) Business Information Systems, Galway-Mayo Institute of Technology

Key Modules Year 4: Business Intelligence, Business Information Systems Analysis & Development, Application Development, Supply Chain Management, Cloud Infrastructure, Enterprise Systems **Expected Result 1:1**

Key Modules Year 3: Web Technology, Data Modelling, Financial management, Business Analytics,

Internship Result: 2:1

2017: Leaving Certificate, St. Mel's College, Longford (447 Points)

Projects:

• Restaurant Website:

For my Internet Technology module, I worked in a team of 4 to create a website for a local restaurant using HTML and CSS in Adobe Dreamweaver. Tasks were divided among the team to manage our time better, as team leader it was my responsibility to ensure everyone completed their tasks.

• Cycle Count Process:

During my internship at Dell Technologies I worked with my mentor to create a process for conducting cycle counts at Dell's Partner facility, DHL Ballycurreen. The process reduced the work load for the inventory control team as well as creating making the reconciliation of cycle counts more accurate.

• Block Chain:

A group project on how modern technology could be used in a business of our choosing. We chose Ryanair. We looked at how the use of block chain could benefit the airline industry. I learned a lot about the potential future uses of blockchain in a variety of sectors.

Key Skills:

- Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Excel, Access, Photoshop, Premiere, Dreamweaver, PowerBi
- Problem solving: Troubleshooting problems with computer systems and data
- Leadership: I have taken a leadership role during group projects in college as well in my role at Camlin Services Ltd.
- Teamwork: Have worked well with others during group projects in college
- Communication: Developed from my work experience and delivering presentations in college

Work Experience:

February 2020 - August 2020: Dell Technologies - Inventory Control

Role: Intern Responsibilities:

Running Queries on Microsoft Access

- Organising physical inventory counts on onsite locations
- Reconciling inventory counts using Excel and Access
- Reconciling cycle counts for DHL

June 2017 - Present: Camlin Service Station

Role: Assistant Manager

Responsibilities:

- Solving technical problems with EPoS till systems
- Key holder, opening the shop on the weekends
- Analysing sales reports
- Operating the tills and assisting customers
- Daily Accounts, cash handling
- Creating orders

June 2014-March 2017: Coffee House 45

Role: Barista
Responsibilities:

- Taking orders and making coffees
- Training new staff
- Daily Accounts, cash handling
- Ordering Stock
- Key holder, opening/closing the shop

Interests & Achievements:

- Full clean driving license
- Excellent attendance award in Secondary School
- Trained in First Aid.
- GDPR training & PCI compliance training
- I enjoy a range of different sports including swimming, running and golf

Referees:

Joseph Raleigh, Managing Director, Camlin Services Ltd. Tel: 043 33 46188

Ronan MacGearailt, Lecturer, Galway-Mayo Institute of Technology, Ronan.MacGearailt@gmit.ie

Niall Mahony, Director, Dell Technologies Inventory Control, Niall Mahony@dell.com